ADAPTED FROM THE BLOSSOMING LOVE
BY SUI YU ER AN ON ICEREAD.COM
MOONLIGHT HEIGHTS
Mr. Gao.
Did you come all the way here
for my daughter's birthday party?
I'm sorry. It's a pity.
The banquet has just ended.
To tell you the truth,
I've come to ask you for someone.
Who can make you make such a request?
Just a spirit slave here,
as long as Mr. Gao agrees
to open the Spirit Lock.
No problem.
You can take any spirit slave you want,
but I'm sorry
you've come so far
and missed
my daughter's birthday party,
so you can stay here for a few days
to let me play a good host.
You are too kind, Mr. Gao,
but there are many
pressing matters in Snow City,
and my father needs me,
so I dare not delay.
I beg your pardon.
Is Snow City in any trouble?
If you need our help,
let me know.
We, the Immortal Alliance,
are in the same boat,
so we should help each other.
That's just Snow City's private business.
I don't want to bother you.
So, when will you
unlock the Spirit Lock?
Don't worry.
Please wait a moment.
I'll ask someone to fetch
the key to Spirit Lock.
Thank you.
I'll wait in the courtyard.
OK.
Ask Supervisor Dai to investigate
which spirit slave
Xie Xuechen is interested in.
Yes, sir.
The spirit slave must be special
to make someone
like Xie Xuechen interested.
In this way,
I can change Ling's future destiny.
Ling.
CLEAR AS MOONLIGHT
You know
it's the Master's daughter's birthday,
but you've been missing all day.
You were not only slacking off
but also stealing.
That was a gift from my Mister.
I didn't steal it.
Miss Gao.
She stole this.
These are not my clothes.
It's getting late.
If you've finished punishing her,
take her away.
Don't disturb my rest.
Good night, Miss Gao.
Even if you didn't steal from her,
you stole from someone else.
Thief.
Really?
How dare you push me?
I didn't expect you
to be so tough.
Supervisor.
What's up?
Mr. Gao wants to tell you
that Snow City's Lord
has his eye on one of our spirit slaves,
so he wants you to secretly find out
who that spirit slave is.
The young man in the morning
was Xie Xuechen,
so the spirit slave he had his eye on…
Sang Qi?
He comes so fast.
Ling.
Mister.
Where are you?
When will you come back and take me away?
Come on. Come on.
What happened?
-Miss Gao.
-Run.
Is this the Gao family's daughter?
Ling.
Ling. Ling.
CLEAR AS MOONLIGHT
She was here.
Your spirit is severely damaged.
If you force time travel again,
you may not be able to return.
Who else is not afraid of death?
Don't be afraid.
It's all right.
I'm taking you away now.
Thank you for saving my life.
Are you the Lord of Snow City,
Xie Xuechen?
Why you?
Why are you wearing her clothes?
Miss Gao. Demons have stormed
the lodge and massacred us.
We can't stay here.
Supervisor Dai.
Find a slave who resembles Miss Gao
and dress her in Miss Gao's clothes.
I'll take her and distract
the Golden Tiger Warrior.
Get Miss Gao out of here with Elder Hua.
When I was a child, you died for me,
and I owed you,
so today,
I'm paying you back.
So, that's what you mean
by "die for you".
Where is Ling?
Where did Ling go?
Elder…
Elder Song took her away.
Where did he take her?
I left first,
so I don't know where they went.
From there, we can leave here.
Let's escape together.
If you can escape,
do it alone,
but remember
that sacrificing others to save yourself
is never the right thing to do.
Gao Qiumin.
Don't become
that kind of person in the future.
It's dangerous inside.
They must have led their pursuers
in the opposite direction.
Ling.
-This way.
-I'm coming.
Stand still.
I'm not the daughter of the Gao family.
You're mistaken.
Spirit slave?
We've been tricked by this old man.
The old man pretended
to protect her to lure us in.
They played it so well.
Then I'll kill her.
-Mister.
-Ling.
Mister. Mister,
you finally came to save me.
I told you I'd take you away.
Go.
How are you hurt?
Mister.
I'm fine.
Really.
Let's go.
Mister.
Mister, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Don't be afraid.
Ling. Don't be afraid.
Why are the demonic patterns on her face
exactly like the sacred patterns
on the Chaos Pearl?
-So…
-Did it hurt?
No,
not at all.
Mister.
I'll be with you
wherever you go from now on.
No wonder Xie Xuechen
asked me for a spirit slave.
He's coveting the Chaos Pearl.
Xie Xuechen.
Give her to me.
What do you mean?
Where's the Spirit Lock key
I asked you for?
Do you still want to play games with me?
I wondered at first
why you asked me
for an insignificant spirit slave,
but until I saw her face,
I realized
this is
what you want.
My nephew. Give her to me.
My spirit is damaged,
and I don't know
how much longer I can last,
so I can't waste my time here
with Gao Fengxu.
Ling.
Wait for me.
I'm going to grab the key to Spirit Lock.
Mister.
Leave me alone.
I'm actually here for you.
My nephew.
You're at the end of your rope,
so I'm afraid you can't
even withstand one of my attacks.
As long as you give her to me,
I can forget about your conspiracy
with Sang Qi to take the Pearl
and your attack on this place.
I think you should know better than me
why Sang Qi chose today to attack.
You are
the Immortal Alliance's Grandmaster,
yet you are greedy
for treasures and power.
A heartless man like you
doesn't deserve her.
You…
It seems you don't need my mercy.
Mister.
Mister. Mister.
Mister, are you alright?
Give her to me,
and I'll spare your life.
Don't be afraid.
Close your eyes.
When you open your eyes,
everything will be fine.
No.
Good girl.
Do as I say.
Okay.
Mister, I will.
Stubborn.
Are you going to destroy
your own spiritual channel?
Mister.
The Chaos Pearl.
Mister, what happened to you?
Mister.
Ling.
Now,
go open the Spirit Lock.
Sang Qi.
Sang Qi is coming.
Now. Now.
We'll go together.
You said you'd take me with you.
You can't lie to me.
I don't want to be alone.
Mister.
Mister, don't die.
Please.
Don't die.
Mister.
Mister, wake up.
I'm just
a spirit slave,
and no one has ever
cared for me or loved me, except you.
You said you'd take me away,
and I believed you.
Ling.
I wasn't upset
when they beat me
-because I thought
-Ling.
you'd take me away soon.
Ling.
Ling. Leave me alone.
Get out of here.
This is…
The Chaos Power.
Ling. Don't do this.
Don't lose your Chaos Power.
Ling.
So…
So, you saved me with the Chaos Power.
You were lucky
to die like that.
If you're so sad,
join him.
Ling.
I can't die.
Do you want revenge?
I can help you,
no matter who you want to take revenge on.
Moonlight Heights,
the Immortal Alliance,
the Humans,
or even
me.
Ling.
Don't trust him. Don't go with him.
Don't.
Ling. Don't.
Come back.
Don't.
Your spirit can't hold out much longer.
Do you really want to die here?
Dad?
There's no time. You must leave.
I went back so many times
just so she could be safe,
but in the end,
the little warmth I gave her
turned into a lifetime of pain
that she couldn't forget
and even killed her.
Xie Xuechen.
Ten years ago,
I saw you in the samsara mirror.
You knew I couldn't save her
even if I went back in time,
but why did you purposely lure me back
to the same mistake?
Do you know
what time is to me?
The beginning is the end.
The first is the last.
I can go back and forth in time and space,
but I am just an observer
who cannot make any changes
to the past or the future.
Likewise,
for High Fate Divinity,
it is the nature of fate.
All endings are revealed
before the beginning,
and all attempts to change destiny
are destiny.
What did I do wrong?
What did Ling do wrong?
Why do we have such a destiny?
I don't understand fate either,
but a man once told me
to wait here for someone
who would solve
the mystery of fate for me.
I thought
you were that person.
You have the Chaos Power.
The Chaos Power
can reverse the outcome.
But I can't even save Ling.
You can.
The Chaos Pearl gave you
what was left of her power,
so she couldn't wake up,
but if you destroy
your own spiritual channel,
the Chaos Power will return to her.
However, in doing so,
you will die.
Completely.
In my mind,
it's not a reborn
but an exchange.
I can save her
by destroying my own spiritual channel.
Did you hear
what I said?
Yes.
Very clearly.
I am merely
returning to her what is rightfully hers.
Anyone who crosses
the Divine Execution Platform
is an idiot.
When I die,
the Chaos Power will return to Ling,
so where will my soul go?
A normal person's soul
will dissipate completely in this world,
but
yours seems to have
survived for 10,000 years,
so it might go somewhere else.
I have a soul that remains in the world.
You are just a tiny fragment of me
remaining in the human realm.
Is my soul really connected
to the Fallen Deity?
Why are you doing this?
I'm using the Jade Vault Technique
to place limits on my soul.
If my soul is captured
by an outlaw after I die,
they will not be able to do evil
with this limitation.
The world should have been at peace.
Ling.
I return all this to you.
That's him.
I told you
you'd come back.
Xie Xuechen.
So, it was you all along.
You
are Mister,
and since you have given me your life,
I will guard the human world
you love for you.
If I accidentally die
one day,
I'll be able to see you.
When that time comes,
don't blame me.
Xie Xuechen.
You left me alone again.
You're finally back.
Nan Xuyue.
How dare you show up again?
It was Xie Xuechen's fate
to die in exchange for your rebirth.
Don't use fate as an excuse.
If you hadn't planned
to kill him with Immortals Array,
how could he have traded
his life for mine?
For all of this,
it's time to put an end to it.
You want to avenge Xie Xuechen,
but not now.
Your body is weak
from the Immortals Array breach.
Also, you just regained the Chaos Power,
so you're not very skilled
at utilizing it.
Your Chaos Power should
be equal to mine,
but at this moment,
you have no chance of winning.
You are not Nan Xuyue.
Who are you?
It seems that regaining the Chaos Power
still hasn't brought back your memories.
It doesn't matter
if you've forgotten me.
Let me introduce myself again.
I am
fate.
You've been in a tough place
like Snow Cliff long enough.
I'm taking you home.
Why did you bring me here?
You and I began in the Foreworld
and were born in Chaos.
We've been together for tens
of thousands of years in the divine realm
and lived only with each other,
and now you don't want to talk to me
and even think I'm an enemy.
It's ironic.
I don't remember
any of this.
All I remember
is that you killed Xie Xuechen.
It's OK if you don't remember.
Fate can't be changed.
No matter what the process is,
the result is the same.
The others are just a moment in time
for you and me.
Only you and I are connected
for eternity.
I'm just Mu Xuanling,
and I never believe in fate.
Some moments are long,
but some long periods
are just a moment.
What matters is who I'm with.
I never cared about eternity
and will never be with you.
I've heard that in this world,
when two people get married,
it'll be for life.
Today is the day
you and I are reunited,
and it's a perfect time.
It is a good day
for us to be married.
I refuse.
All I think about
is Xie Xuechen.
Whether I live or die,
I only do it for Xie Xuechen.
Our marriage doesn't depend
on whether you want it or not.
Because you
don't have a choice.
Two Realms Mountain has an anomaly.
The demonic energy is so strong.
It seems a new demon
has been born in this world.
I've never seen
such a strange phenomenon
in all my years of cultivation.
But the Void Sea has been sealed,
and the Immortals Array
has been rebuilt, so have we
missed someone from the Dark Clan?
TEMPLE OF DIVINE EXECUTION
Such powerful demonic energy does not come
from ordinary ones of the Dark Clan.
I'm afraid it's far stronger
than Sang Qi's.
That's impossible.
I've been to the Dark Abyss many times,
but I've never seen
anyone stronger than Sang Qi.
TEMPLE OF DIVINE EXECUTION
Who are you?
Xie Xuechen?
Now that the sects are without a leader,
and the Dark Abyss
may cause trouble again,
the sects of the Immortal Alliance
should work together.
Everyone, gather your elite disciples
and go with me to Two Realms Mountain
to find out what's going on.
Yes.
Bao.
Are you going
with them?
Stay in Snow City
and wait for me.
Be safe.
I'm speaking for my mom.
She's waiting for you.
OK.
How dare you come to the Dark Abyss again?
Good.
Then, let's have a good fight today.
I'll make you a corpse
before you get out of here.
Why can you use demonic power?
Trap him with Prison of Lust.
You overestimated yourselves.
TEMPLE OF DIVINE EXECUTION
You're afraid?
A warrior's destiny
is either victory or death.
And those who are cowardly in battle
deserve to die.
Who are you?
I am
Zhao Ming.
You are the Fallen Deity
who was suppressed in the Lava Chasm?
You are still alive?
I don't want to hear
the word "the Fallen Deity" again.
Next time,
you die.
It's time to change
the rules of the Dark Abyss.
From this moment on,
it's no longer the law of the jungle.
It's the law of me.
Those who obey me
live.
Those who fight me die.
Long live the Demon Lord.
Ten thousand years have passed,
and my old friend is waiting for me.
It's time to catch up.
Master. Miss Mu won't change.
We've been persuading her for a long time.
It's all right.
Leave us alone.
Yes.
You've gone mad.
I'm sober.
I know you don't want
to wear a wedding dress
because you want to mourn for Xie Xuechen.
I won't force you.
If you wear all black and white,
I will too.
That would be a good match.
Since you're fate,
how can you believe in mortal marriage?
Of course, I don't believe in it,
but I know
you've always wanted to have
this ceremony with Xie Xuechen
and hold hands with him
in the presence of heaven and earth
until you die.
I can give you
what Xie Xuechen can give you.
I don't need you to love me,
but just to be there for me.
The future is long,
so I just hope we can
always be there for each other.